Forget about love.
Nymphomaniac: Vol. II is a drama, mystery film directed by Lars von Trier.
The continuation of Joe's sexually dictated life delves into the darker aspects
of her adult life and what led to her being in Seligman's care.
Joe, played by Charlotte Gainsbourg.
Seligman, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Young Joe, played by Stacy Martin.
Jerôme, played by Shia LaBeouf.
L, played by Willem Dafoe.
The Waiter, played by Udo Kier.
Nymphomaniac (stylised as NYMPH()MANIAC onscreen and in advertising, and sometimes as
NYMPH(;)MANIAC) is a 2013 erotic art film written and directed by Lars von Trier.
The film stars Charlotte Gainsbourg, Stellan Skarsgård, Stacy Martin, Shia LaBeouf, Christian Slater, Jamie Bell, Uma Thurman,
Jean-Marc Barr, Willem Dafoe, Connie Nielsen, and Mia Goth; both Martin and Goth appeared in their film debut.
Separated into two films, the plot follows Joe (played by Gainsbourg and Martin), a self-diagnosed
"nymphomaniac" who recounts her erotic experiences to a bachelor who helps her recover from an assault.
The narrative chronicles Joe's promiscuous life from adolescence to
adulthood and is split into eight chapters told across two volumes.
The film was originally supposed to be only one complete entry, but, because of its length,
von Trier made the decision to split the project into two separate films.
Nymphomaniac was an international co-production of
Denmark, Belgium, France, and Germany.
The world premiere of the uncut Volume I occurred on 16 February 2014 at the 64th Berlin International Film
Festival, while the uncut Volume II premiered at the 71st Venice International Film Festival.
The world premiere of the Director's Cut took place
in Copenhagen on 10 September 2014.
It was nominated for the 2014 Nordic Council Film Prize.
Nymphomaniac is the third and final installment in von Trier's unofficially
titled Depression Trilogy, following Antichrist and Melancholia.
The film explores themes of bondage, whip, sexuality, masochism, sex therapy.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.